ROSTISLAV VATOLIN

+1 832 983 3965 vatolinrp@icloud.com 2651 Kipling Street, Houston, TX 77098

Main tech stack: Java, Spring Framework, SQL, Docker, Kubernetes, JUnit, Mockito

Knowledge of cloud providers: Microsoft Azure, Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud Platform

Implemented integration with: Oracle DB, Azure Cosmos DB (Graph DB), Amazon Dynamo DB, Redis Cache, Gemfire Cache, Azure Service Bus, Apache Kafka

PROFILE

Senior Software Engineer with more than 7 years of Java development experience. Proven practical expertise in the development of REST and SOAP web-services. Strong knowledge of AWS, GCP, and Azure cloud infrastructure technology stacks. Experienced follower of Scrum and Kanban methodologies. Great mentoring skills with experience of coaching a group of software engineers. Experience in business domains: Travel & Hospitality, E-commerce, Energy. Impressive results in writing unit and integration tests.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer, EPAM SYSTEMS, Client in Energy domain, Houston, USA - 2020-Present

Key-developer role on the project. Client maintains a heavy backend system to manage data in Oil and Gas industry. Actively contributed to open source solution called OSDU. Developed cloud agnostic solution using Java and Spring framework. Configured and deployed on Kubernetes in Microsoft Azure. Implemented unit and integration tests with JUnit and Mockito.

Senior Software Engineer, EPAM SYSTEMS, Client in Telecommunication domain, Belarus - 2019-2020

Developer role on the project. E-commerce project using SAP Hybris 1808 with Telco & Media Accelerator 1810. Monolithic architecture. Support and feature development using Java 8 and Spring framework. Test coverage using JUnit and Mockito. Continuous integration with Apache Ant and Jenkins. Deployment done in AWS Cloud environment.

Senior Software Engineer, EPAM SYSTEMS, Client in Heavy Building materials domain, Belarus - 2018-2019

Developer role on the project. Developed new functionality using Java 8. Deployment carried over to AWS Lambda. Worked on persistence layer for integration with AWS DynamoDB. Build and deployment done using Maven and Jenkins. Unit tests with JUnit and Mockito.

Software Engineer, EPAM SYSTEMS, Client in Travel & Hospitality domain, Belarus - 2015-2018

Developer role on the project. Created new functionality (REST APIs), enhanced existing in project's middleware area using Java 8, Spring framework, Apache Camel. Ensured enterprise systems integration with Active MQ and Apache Kafka. Carried deployments of OSGi bundles to on

Efficient in developing: REST and SOAP APIs, microservice and monolith applications.

CI/CD done using Azure DevOps, Jenkins, Maven, Gradle on-premise Redhat JBoss Fuse server. Worked on integration with Oracle 11 database (created SQL queries), Gemfire cache. Ensured high quality of code by creating unit tests using JUnit and Mockito. Developed and supported CI/CD with the help of Maven and Gradle build tools, continuous integration with Jenkins.

EDUCATION

Belarusian State University — Bachelor degree in Computer Science

INTERESTS

Architecture, high-load systems, CI/CD, Clean code, tech literature.